### VEDANG R. VATSA

### Head of Marketing at Entrepreneurship Cell, IIT Kanpur

IIT Kanpur | +919416779705 | vedang@iitk.ac.in

vedangvats.com in www.linkedin.com/in/vedangvatsa

### COVER

I am an initiator and the one who get things done. I developed my skills and worked with some eminent clients on my own.

I like to travel far up to the mountains and deep down to the beaches with an aim to explore the strong possibilities of reality. I love to discuss ideas with people and appreciate honest feedback.

I have always felt the hunger to achieve more. I love to master new skills with an idea of expanding the domain of my expertise and knowledge.

Keywords: Team Management, Entrepreneurship, Negotiations, Media, Consulting, Analytics, Copywriting,

Sales, Designing, Public Relations, Marketing, Business development and Social Media

### **EDUCATION**

#### M.B.A (Dept. of IME)

2017 - Present

SKILLS

UI/UX

Sales and Marketing

Review • Presentation

Graphic Designing

Digital Marketing

CERTIFICATIONS

Garage

Mile Learning

Leadership Academy

Applications from MIIT

C / C++ from CS Infotech

Blockchain and its Applications

International Journal of Research

StartupIndia, Ministry of Commerce and

India- China Relations taking a turn and how

India can balance out its Relationship with US

Leadership Effectiveness, Spiritual Values and

Leading Today : Since their first published

article in January 2001, weLEAD has become

Avant Garde : Official MBA Newsletter of IIT

A Case Study on 'The Mobile Applications

Imperial Journal of Interdisciplinary Research

(IJIR) Vol-3, Issue-9, 2017 ISSN: 2454-1362;

Current Trends and Approaches of Network

Mobile Computing; ISSN: 2320-088X; Vol. 6,

Raspberry Pi based Implementation of

Internet of Things using Mobile Messaging

Applications, Foundation of Computer Science,

Comparative Analysis of Coverage Schemes in

Communications on Applied Electronics - CAE,

International Journal of Computer Technology

Emerging of New Service Oriented Approach

 International Journal of Advanced Research in Computer and Communication Engineering Vol.

Foundation of Computer Science, New York,

International Journal of Computer Science and

one of the most comprehensive leadership, and management development websites on the

**PUBLICATIONS** 

Industry, Govt. of India

the Paths to Happiness

Psychology of Colors

Impact Factor - 3.75

Intrusion Detection System

Application - Telegram

Jul 2016

Jun, 2016

USA.

Systems

Jun 2016

New York, USA.

Issue. 6, June 2017, pg.266 - 270

International Journal of Computer

WSN (Wireless Sensor Network)

Jul 23, 2018

and China

Jun 26, 2018

Jun 10, 2018

Internet!

Kanpur

Industry'

Sep 30, 2017

Growth Hacking • Partnership and

Collaborations • Business Development

· Web · Mobile · Wireframes and Mockups

Consulting | Strategy and Research

Strategy • Academic • Qualitative • Literature

Social Media Marketing
Campaign Marketing

Content Writing • Copywriting • SEO Analysis

 The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing : Endorsed by IAB Europe by Google Digital

· Presentation skills by Humanitarian

Photoshop: : Diploma in Computer

Introduction to Copywriting from Udemy

Inbound Marketing from Hubspot Academy

Introduction to Financial Management by Last

Art direction
Branding and Advertisement

Visual Identity • Media posts • Posters

### Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur

- International delegate for HPAIR by Harvard University at Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
- Youth delegate for the India-Venezuela Youth Dialogue 2018 among 60 delegates from India.
- · Departmental Post Graduate Committee (DPGC) representative for MBA, Dept. of IME, IIT Kanpur
- Head of Marketing in Entrepreneurship-Cell, IIT Kanpur
- Overall Coordinator: Impressions Annual PG Cultural Festival
- Senior Executive in SIP and Web verticals in E Cell, IIT Kanpur
- Senior Executive in Academics and Research Cell International Relations
- Coordinator in PR and Media Cell; Avant-garde (Official MBA Newsletter) Anchoring in Entrepreneurship Summit organized by E Cell, IIT Kanpur
- Coordinator: Media, Design, PR and Marketing in Prabandhan (Annual Management Conclave)

### M.Tech (Computer Science)

### Maharshi Dayanand University

· Won the title of 'Mr. Fresher'

· Research Paper on 'Security in Ubiquitous Computing-Location Based Applications' In National Conference on Recent Trends and Developments in Statistics (UGC SAP Sponsored)

 Review Paper on 'Study and Analysis of Security Threats and Attacks in MANET' In National Conference on Recent Trends and Developments in Statistics (UGC SAP Sponsored)

Review Paper on 'A Literature Review on Internet of Things (IoT) '

Presented a prototype model on 'Raspberry Pi based low-cost laptop' At IIT-Delhi (TRYST-2015)

In International Journal of Computer Systems, Volume 2, Issue 8, August 2015, pages: 355-358

- Thesis on 'Video surveillance system using Telegram application running on Raspberry Pi"
- Worked on a prototype for 'Virtual Reality headset based on Raspberry Pi and Arduino' and 'Control of electrical switches wirelessly using smartphone based on the concept of the Internet of Things'
- Participated in 'Arduino' workshop at TRYST-2015, IIT-Delhi

### B.E. (Computer Science & Engineering) Panjab University

2009 - 2013

2013 - 2015

- Executive head of the Training and Placement Cell.
- Member of the technical committee of college's Techno-Cultural Fest; Hostel Committee.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### ENTREPRENEURSHIP CELL, IIT KANPUR Head of Marketing

Apr 2018 - Present

### While 'Entrepreneurship' is growing to be one of the business world's biggest buzzwords, the E- Cell at IIT

Kanpur envisions a time, when youth will look up to the new generation of CEOs and entrepreneurs as their modern-day rock stars. Motivated by this vision, we are a team of an enthusiastic bunch of people at E-Cell, working to induce an

entrepreneurial mindset into the students and to air an innovative streak in them. HARVARD PROJECT FOR ASIAN AND INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS

#### International Delegate Selected as a delegate (among 600) from a highly selective pool of international applicants to attend the Harvard Project for Asian and International Relations (HPAIR) Conference in Kuala Lumpur by Harvard

### ■ INDIA-VENEZUELA YOUTH DIALOGUE '18

University.

Youth Delegate Selected (among 60) as the youth delegate for India Venezuela Youth Dialogue 2018.

May 2018 - July 2018

### Management Intern Noida, India

ERNST & YOUNG

Base Erosion and Profit Shifting: India perspective and OECD's focus on action plans: Literature Review, India Perspective and OECD's focus on Action Plans. The work included a case study on the given topic based on EY experience while servicing the clients,

maintaining the confidentiality of the client at the same time. The deliverable by Vedang included an academic review of the literature on BEPS and a formal report that included the introduction of the action plans, a brief explanation of OECD BEPS action plan, India perspective and area of impact OMIDYAR NETWORK

## Live Project

Civic Tech India 2018 in association with Village Capital

GOFOODIEONLINE

Marketing Consulting, Social Media Marketing, SEO Analysis

### ENTREPRENEURSHIP CELL, IIT KANPUR Senior Executive

Marketing Consultant

 Vertical: SIP(Startup Internship Program) The work includes initiating a conversation with the founders and the HR recruiters of various startups and

to convert them to offer summer internships to the students of IIT Kanpur: B.Tech, BS, B.Tech+M.Tech, BS+MS. ■ TRAVART | GEDIT ECOMMERCE PRIVATE LIMITED Jan 2018 - Jul 2018

### Media campaigns/ Marketing, Social Media Engagements, Business Development and Advertising Consulting

IMPRESSIONS: ANNUAL PG CULTURAL FESTIVAL Overall Coordinator - IIT Kanpur

### Events included: Fashion Show, Solo Dance, Singing, Dramatics, Band performance, Group Dance, Poetry, and Standups

- Lead a team of 15 members Designed and developed the website Handled social media
- Designed the posters

Management Intern

- Managed the finances Logistics: Get the required permissions from various departments (Security, DOSA, Gymkhana, etc.)
- HINDUSTAN PETROLEUM CORPORATION LIMITED

Publicity on Facebook (from 1700 to 3600+ likes)

### Delhi, India Sales analytics - Development of an analytics tool to monitor sales data.

Hindustan Petroleum Corporation Limited (HPCL) is an Indian state-owned oil and natural gas company with its headquarters at Mumbai, Maharashtra. The government of India owns 51.11% shares in HPCL. The

E CELL, VIT VELLORE Campus Ambassador

company is ranked 367th on the Fortune Global 500 list of the world's biggest corporations as of 2016.

The core responsibilities is to make people aware of the various events in ESummit'18 and to make sure that more participation may be within the campus.

### THE MINIMALIST Live Project

STUDIO TESSERACT

Market Survey, Analysis, Research and creation of end to end business plan.

IT Consultant Ghaziabad, India

the timeline and the cost involved. Branding: Design and illustration for different client projects. Project Management: Making sure that the team working on the project understands the requirements

Business development: Approaching a client from various online platforms, negotiating them concerning

UI Design: Designing the UI/UX for mobile applications and websites along with prototyping - using Adobe Photoshop and Invision.

thoroughly and follow the agile methodology to progress further.

DELL Services

Software Development Intern Noida, India

Worked on the development of an intranet web portal.

A Review on the Multi Modal Biometric

& Applications, Vol 7(3), 374-384

Based on Internet of Things

Oct 2017 - Dec 2017 Social Media Marketing

Aug 2017 - Apr 2018

5, Issue 5, May 2016; Impact Factor - 5.332 A Literature Review on Internet of Things International Journal of Computer Systems

Sponsored)

Sponsored)

Dec 2017

Oct 2017 - Nov 2017

Sep 2015 - Jul 2017

May 2010 - Jul 2010

(ISSN: 2394-1065), Volume 02 - Issue 08, August, 2015 Security in Ubiquitous Computing-Location **Based Applications** 

Feb 2015 National Conference on Recent Trends and Developments in Statistics (UGC SAP

 Study and Analysis of security threats and attacks in MANET Feb 2015 National Conference on Recent Trends and

**ACHIEVEMENTS** 

i24', 'Jewish Business News', 'Boston

Developments in Statistics (UGC SAP

### · One of the projects that I was a part of, has been featured in 'The Times of Israel', 'News

Business Journal', 'Bostinno', 'MedCity News', 'VentureFizz', etc. Presented a prototype model on 'Raspberry Pi based low cost laptop' At IIT-Delhi (TRYST-2015), appreciated by people including Nobel Laureate: Physics, Head : MIT Media Labs,

NASA Astronaut, CEOs of invited companies and Professors of IIT Delhi and IIT Kharagpur. Some of my clients include: The screenwriter for 89th Annual Academy Awards (Oscars), 68th Primetime Emmy Awards and Jimmy Kimmel Live

 IS&T Project Manager at Apple, Founder of Crush & Craft Eran Malovani : Founder and CEO – CPA+ (Israel)

Runner's Up: Pitch Ur Product in

Entrepreneurship Summit at IIT Kanpur

Public Speaking • Leadership • Team

ADILITIES

Management • Entrepreneurship • Client Communication & Feedback

# VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

 Rotaract Midtown, Chandigarh - ISKCON -UN Volunteers . AEIY . Kartar Asra

## OTHER INTERESTS

Meditation

mics, anchoring in Esummit'17 - IITK)

 Adventure Sports (Jumped the world's highest Canyon Swing and from India's highest

Photography (7000+ followers on Instagram)

bungee jumping platform)

 Traveling (Traveled to 3 countries solo) Public Speaking (Performed in various open